I got a real question for y'all.
So, I want y'all to explain to me, how do you think things will change if you get Democrats in office?
Hayley O'Neill, someone said I'm always online.
I think your versions of always are fascinating.
Let me tell you what I've done today.
I went swimming today.
I had an entire call to plan a retreat to Grenada.
I played with my dog and cats.
I lost my nose ring and had to go find something to replace it in the meantime.
So, that's what this giant orb in my nose is.
I started fixing my website.
So, I did all of that.
But y'all talking about you stay online.
I took a shower and washed my hair.
I do more in a day than most people do in a week.
And I do more in a week than most people do in a month.
Charles.
You see what Charles Lowe said?
A man that is in that house thinking.
I was in the pool thinking today.
I was in the car thinking today.
Like, but that being said.
Actually, Charles, I would love to hear your thoughts on this.
Charles, come online.
Will you come on my live?
I would love for you to ask.
I would love to hear your thoughts.
Please tell me Charles will come online.
I want a smart man talking.
I don't know if he's still there.
The supertism.
That's right.
My autism is very.
It'd be ADHD and when it want to.
No, it's not a manic episode.
That's how I've been my whole life.
Because it's not a manic episode.
Because it doesn't go in waves.
This is how I exist.
Okay.
Like, a manic episode is like you do it all.
Do it all.
And then you stop.
And you burn out.
And then you do it all.
Do it all.
I am in my local library.
Which means it's all black people.
This is in the south near my house.
One of my favorite interviews when I interviewed you and you was like, I didn't see white people
because I was like 18.
You was like, I'm really from a black sit town in Louisiana.
So what is your question?
How do you think things will change?
Were Democrats to then replace who is in office now?
So I think I, I, I, I, I, I believe, you know, first of all, you're trapped in a two-party system.
Uh, and until that changes, uh, and until that changes, you're just, you're, you're in it.
Uh, and, uh,
How do you change it then?
Well, well, well, first thing I always say is you, you have to know the difference between the friend that disappoints you
and the enemy who wants to destroy you and so I actually, I think that they are friendlier
and disappointments, but friendlier, uh, because the principles there are destruction.
Uh, whether or not it is, um, liberation involved in the platform, no, that's not what it is,
but it is not destruction.
And so can you, you say it's not destruction.
I don't think it is destruction of the country.
I don't think it is.
Uh, I think that the, the Republicans at this point have just kind of given up on the idea
that, uh, that, that anything here is salvageable or redeemable.
People, they would like to destroy it all, uh, and, uh, in that wreckage that they will believe
that they will have benefits.
Uh, I believe that anarchy comes after destruction.
I believe that, uh, that, that this has always suffered the most in the middle of anarchy and
destruction.
Uh, and when I look at people who has the most resources and access,
uh, in, uh, in a, in the wake of a destruction, those people will have a better chance of survival
than people who don't.
I think a lot of, you know, um, Mike, Mike, big Mike, killer Mike, uh, said this thing a
long time ago.
I actually wrote in my last book, he was talking about black people and saying, everybody wants
to, uh, be a revolutionary.
He was like, who in here fishes?
Who in here hunts?
Who in here?
Like when it, when it comes down to like a real, um, Hey, how are you, sir?
Uh, when it comes down to like, uh, a real destruction of society, which is what they
want and what some people will say that they want, who are revolutionary, like, like tear
it all down.
Uh, how do you survive in that is a real question with limited resources or no resources and
also no survival skills that you would need in that kind of environment.
And the idea of like, you know, I'm from the country, like here, you know, people grow
things all the time.
You hunt all the time.
Like you could, I could go off the grid here and live.
Uh, I live in Atlanta now.
And I know that none of my neighbors could do that.
I lived in New York for a very long time.
I know nobody that I knew there could do that.
And so the idea of like, opting out of the system is, becomes a luxury of preparation.
And a lot of people who would like to do it are just not prepared to do it.
And who, who, and so I, so my, my thing is like, I need the destruction to stop, to, to
have a base from which to build a better society.
And I think, you know, this destructive mentality is just not good for us.
I feel like, are you, are you frozen?
I think he's frozen.
No, I'm here.
Oh.
Jordy.
Come here.
Quit playing with me.
Um, I feel like when, when, okay.
When people say destroy the system.
Yeah.
It doesn't mean destroy society.
It means destroy the means by which we don't have a society.
Like our society operates in an incredibly destructive.
fashion in the United States. And the United States is not the only society. You got to go
inside. You got to go inside because you act crazy. Go inside. Go inside. Okay. So what do
you mean? If you say destroy system, what do you mean? First of all, we have a capitalist system
that both Republicans and Democrats have not only bought into, but have spent the duration of this
country's existence propping up and continuing to establish as the only method by which society
can operate. Even though we do have socialist systems within our capitalist system, it seeks to
not only denigrate socialism, but at this point now criminalize anyone who is willing to suggest
that that be how we operate. So it literally chooses to lose socialism.
So I would say, let's mark that and say, I agree with almost all of what you just said. So let's
mark that we agree on that. So then now from that position, how do we get to destroying that system?
I personally believe that your methodology that you, your methodology in The Devil You Know
of saying that we need to move back into spaces where we are choosing to take control. I think
that is the directive. I think the thing is though, is that where I would, I think where I would
pivot, where I would detour, diverge, Lord, it wasn't there.
It wasn't, it wasn't there. I was never going to find it. I was never going to find it. It wasn't
even right here. It wasn't on the tip of my tongue. So thank you. Where I diverge from you is
we, as people in the United States have become so accustomed to existing with this overlord,
which is literally how we have been trained religiously, right? To really trust and believe
in this like overlord who we don't even know what they're doing. They're just doing things and we
find out about it and then it happens. And unless you are really, really, really, really, really tapped
in and you're, you know, getting the notices like shit changes and you don't even know. So we are
trained spiritually and religiously to continue to keep up this establishment that has this overlord
overhead that is doing whatever and we are just following it. That being said, we no longer have
jurisdiction over the way that we operate because corruption has come down to the local level.
So we have to, on a local level, not simply just participate. We have to be policing the way
this is even functioning to the point where we say, this is not functionable. I strongly believe
that we should have folks whose only job is to be looking at politicians and saying,
this doesn't work, so we're going to do this. Not just going, this doesn't work, so we're not going
to vote for you. Saying, you're not working, you're not doing anything, so we're doing this thing over
here. We have that in many cases, though. It ends up needing to feed into the government system in
order to get funding, etc. So when we talk about the shifting and the destabilizing of systems,
first of all, we have been given the greatest blueprints for destabilizing the systems by the
United States. All the United States does is go over the world, all over the world, and destabilize
systems. And they destabilize them by coming in and saying, we're going to do the thing that you guys
we're doing yourselves, and we're going to make it so that you can't do it. That's what we should
be doing. We should literally be the ones doing it ourselves and saying, we don't need you.
We don't need you, government. We don't need you. We don't need you. And the only way that we figure
out how to do that is if we decide we don't need them. Now, what I will also add is that-
I'm sorry. So here's the part. So you say,
needing to get to the point where you say you don't need the government? I'm trying to make
sure I understand. We don't need this particular government. No. The only way that you-
This one here, but you need government in general, but not this one.
You need government in general, but you don't need government to govern in this fashion. There's
many, many, many, many forms of governments. And there's been many forms of governance long before
we even had monarchies, etc. You know, there are even in present day, like the Zapatistas in Mexico,
they have a government that operates as a committee. I mean, it's not, I mean, even our
schools have quote unquote governments. I mean, the PTA operates as a government for the school,
so to speak. So we have all of these frameworks, but we are so stuck in this idea that this is the
only thing that works. And I believe it is also because we have been programmed to believe that
it is the best, that the USA is the best. It is not by any means. And the last thing I'll say is
there's just simply nothing to save in a government that is run bipartisan by Zionism, period.
You know, like you asked me on October 11th, should Israel exist? And I was like, don't ask me that
because they're going to come for me. And I will tell you today, no, no, it should not exist.
It is an apartheid state. It is a scourge on the fucking earth. And at the end of the day,
no nation that operates with such violence for not only its citizens, but also the people
it's displacing and also the people that it is neighbors to should be allowed to continue
to exist unencompassed. I mean, sorry, unhindered. No. And so by part, like you think, you think the
Democrats are going to stop sending our money there so that we can get what we need here?
I would do. I do. I do. I know that the last land arming selling arms was there were a lot
of Democrats who were voting against that. But I will I will say this, though, I want to
say there's never enough, though. And that's my training, my training as a citizen of the
country and as a person in the community, as you just described, comes from a very, very particular
place. So I can't divorce myself from who I am as a how I grew up. And that means I just grew up
around in spaces where black people had government and ourselves on local levels. And it just it was
all the way from, like you said, like school boards and whatever. But things that didn't work didn't
work. And black people would say it doesn't work and we would change it. And so I come from that
kind of a sense of what community participatory democracy, small d feels like when the community
says what works, what doesn't. And they are able to change that. That does not mean that the that
that that that negation.
Black people are in charge of things. It just changed my view of how participatory democracy
can operate. And because it was so spaces were small, which weren't governed by who could spend
the most money. It was a community. It was a community consciousness that was governing it.
And so and whether or not that can scale up is very much a question. But that is just where I am
rooted in the experiment of democracy in America. I'm just I cut my teeth in that space. And so I
I'm biased towards that kind of a view. That's literally what I just said.
No, I don't think we're doing. I'm just coming from your bias. You disagree with me.
Okay. You guys you disagree with me. The problem is that that
that is not how people continue to see things like folks at that time felt powerful in their
in their segregation to handle themselves. And I would say that when when capitalism became widely
available to all of us, it left behind all of us, like because even those who have been able to
make money. So for instance, like I was able to make money being on television.
But it doesn't mean that my money can effectively disrupt the efforts that capitalism makes to
prevent people from being able to just live like I can change, you know, people's lives to a certain
extent. But the system itself is so committed at this point, that it doesn't even make it possible
to cut through. I mean, like I just saw Jerry Rice and his wife just spent six hundred and sixty
seven thousand some odd dollars to clear lunch debt for kids. Like, why is that something that has to be
done? What? Why does a citizen have to clear a lunch debt?
Right. Let me let me add one more wrinkle to this conversation about capitalism is that it doesn't
it is not always as predacious when income inequality is not existing to the degree that it exists now.
Part of what I would argue, though, I would argue that that's an argument based in what I would argue about
that. And I'm just gonna I know I'm cutting you off, but I have to go anyway. But the reason why that
argument to me is is a fallacy is because capitalism is a is a system that gets worse as it continues. So you
can't really you can't really you can't really critique it or or commit or analyze it based on
previous time frames to the present, because at the end of the day, it's where we are now that is the
result. Like, that's why we can say, like, OK, we have seen corporations make dividends to this height
up until this point. However, we haven't seen any raises happen in employment. We have I wasn't even
making it. I wasn't even making a I wasn't making a longitudinal critique about, you know, now versus
then expansion. I was just saying I was saying that in community. Again, I'm just I'm because I'm here.
I just kind of like my brain is in community where the disparities between, you know, the who, you know,
the income levels, it's just so small that there was just a there's a common sense of necessity,
what is right, what is because that's what is proper. Small communities like what you've described
exist as socialist communities. OK, because no one can get left behind because it's so small that
leaving anyone behind is like a it's like a community act of cruelty. You know, and so if you're there,
you have to be there. As a site of responsibility, even just because even just to avoid the shame.
Right. Right. Yeah. Listen, I agree with that. I mean, I saw this one guy who went around
the indigenous societies because he was looking for a cure for his son. He had a disease. But he
one thing he recognized was like in indigenous societies, nobody gets left behind. Oh, you're
crazy. Oh, you're just a witch doctor. Like that's the job of everybody. Like there's no like no one's out.
Uh, and I think that that applies to smaller communities in America. Like this.
It doesn't matter. You have to there's a role for you in the community. Like you will,
we will honor it and we will respect it. And these places may be homophobic, but oh,
you play the piano. Yeah. Yeah. You don't like it. And not only do you play it at church.
Listen, you better. Like in Grenada. There's this artist in Grenada. It's the whole thing.
He is very clearly autistic. He lives in a hut, the size, not a shack, the size of my porch.
His entire, I don't even know who paid for the land. I don't even know if he owned the land,
but he owned this land. And when you pull up, he done made all type of structures and all type
of shit. And the shops in tongue are now selling his art. And baby, I was, I was at one of the shops
and she was like, I was like asking about him and she was like, well, you know, we got a lot of blue
fish because someone gave him blue paint. So we have a lot of blue fish right now.
And, and all I thought of was someone came and brought this man paint.
Cause they know he'd be painting.
That's what you do. That's what he does, you know, and somebody's feeding him.
Right. Somebody is. And so, so what I feel like, I think that's, I think that's socialism,
community things. Like it's a, it's just part of, I mean, the question is, how do you scale it?
Because it is very much a part of smaller, like somebody dies in this neighborhood.
They don't clean or cook for a week. The community just shows up. My brother died. Like people just
showed up. Like, I don't know who he's like, they were cleaning, they were cooking. It's just what
happens. One goes hungry and maybe step into this, but my mother just cooks extra on Sundays and
everybody who she knows is struggling or dealing with something, they get a plate. It's just so,
so, but she's also paying taxes to a system. And that, you know, part of me thinks like that,
those tax dollars should go to doing this. You're actually doing this in your after,
out of your after tax funds. Uh, but how do you up, uh, a sense of community,
empathy and caring is, and, and take that out of a purely financially profit motivated,
uh, sensibility. And that, you know, it's a question, you know, it's kind of more philosophical.
Now I get, but I get, but as you said, you have to go, I have to go back here. So keep writing.
We're going to be forced out of it, by the way, though, like we're going to be forced out of it.
Like whether it's by Democrats or Republicans or who's actually running both of them, which is the
central bank and the world bank, like we're going to be forced out of it. And when killer Mike talks
about like, oh, well, can you fish? It's like, well, no, you can fish though. But you know what I can
do? I can season the like, we all have, I can bandage your wound like a yes, I can. I can bandage
your wound. And you? Yeah. My mom's a nurse. You can make a tourniquet? Oh. Yeah. I can do all of that
shit. I, someone got cut in the airport and I had to pull out my first aid kit and, and whip it up.
Whip it up. Like everybody doesn't need to have the same skill. And if you know how to think,
I don't, I don't, I don't, I don't even say everybody, I don't think, I don't think individually
have to have it, but I, I, I think I took his point, which is my point is that's a very extreme
thought process to think that we going to be driving Benzes and not eating the fish and not
knowing how to fish. Like we're like, there's no version of like, this all goes to, to shit because
we want socialism, unless it's a nuclear scenario. Like that's just not how it happens. Um, and we
have seen countries fall, but not enough Americans have. And that's why there's a fear. That's why
there's a fear. Do you think mom, Danny is, is a, is a, how do you think he's doing it? And do you
think that that is something that's transferable? I think mom, Danny is, um, not consistent enough for
my taste. Um, and I'm still waiting to see, you know, like when I see Chelsea arrested outside of,
you know, the, the, the, the, the house that's being stolen, um, he's being arrested by
the cops that mom Donnie's the boss of. So I'm like, nobody can make a call. Nobody can make a call.
Like he got a concussion. Y'all was together at Shabbat Lubavitch, which you shouldn't have been at,
but she was together there dancing around with Jermaine and it looked like, okay, well,
we're going to make friends with all of these folks. Um, but at the end of the, like, I saw him
go and, and, and, and, and, you know, bow to the, the, the, the pedophilic violent, um, cult leaders,
uh, what's it called? Um, tomb. And so at a certain point, it's like, I, you know,
I know that everyone loves to say like, well, you know, sometimes you got to kiss the ring.
It's politics. And that's why we are where we are because we're still doing the kiss the ring
politics. And we keep kissing the ring of people who keep punching us in the face.
And at what point do we say, you know what, it's time to be Malcolm and Martin before his death,
because Martin also eventually was like, yeah, I done. I, I fucked up y'all.
So I'm always fascinated by this conversation because I always wonder how,
I want you to explain to me then how does a person get elected? The question is because
Martin before his death is incredibly unpopular. So it's like, it's a great thing that he's a civil
rights leader, not a politician, because he would not have been elected. So how does a person get
elected? Or do you not believe that the part that are we going to be post politician? Or are we like,
I don't know, we do need to be post politician, but if he gets elected,
then with that, there needs to be shifting. And I'm still waiting to see how extreme the shifting will be.
Like, is it just doing the basic stuff that should be done? Or is it making,
you know, enroads for things to last after he's out of office? Because that's the thing. It's like,
folks do just enough for the time they're there, but it's not last. It's not able to be lasting,
which is why Democrats are full of shit, because they never do things that actually have longstanding
effects. They always just do enough to make it look like they did something,
but it can be completely reversed once the regime changes and the wings flip on the bird.
And that is why we don't see, that's why Roe v. Wade wasn't codified, right? That's why
we don't have a George Floyd anti policing bill. Why is the 13th Amendment not even challenged by any
Democrats when it literally says slavery is legal? Like, why aren't these things actually addressed
that are disenfranchising the entire nation? So on a federal level, you have these major,
major, major issues that are just simply not being addressed and cemented by Democrats. And then when
it's time, the evil Republicans come in, they flip, and then the Democrats can go, look, the evil
Republicans, and then they flip and they just keep us in a cycle while they continue to actually make
money and destabilize the rest of the world. But you believe that you be earthquake kind of change
is possible in a political system? No, I think it's possible to shake the earth enough to
depoliticize the system. We need public servants. We need, and for what it's worth, I do think the
United States is too big. We're an empire and empires are, the reason why the Ottoman empire was able
to last as long as it did was because it let people just live. It was like, okay, we're going to run
shit and you're going to have to pay us some taxes. But like, if y'all, if y'all, we all do y'all,
you know, do what you need to do. And so actually, I won't even say the reason why it lasted so long.
The reason why cultures and ethnicities and traditions that existed within the Ottoman empire
were able to continue to last was because of that. Because they said, we rule this, but you can do you.
And I want to see that. I want to see the world change. I'm gonna be here for it. So people keep
being like, Amanda, be safe. I'm like, I'm gonna be here. It's gonna be annoying, but I'm gonna still
be here. All right. Signing on to the lies. Take care. Thank you for coming. Thank you for coming.
All right, y'all. I have a call that I forgot was scheduled, but I hope you enjoyed that conversation.
I think it was really useful. And I think it was also very demonstrative of how you can have different
viewpoints and still have a really respectful discourse that advances thoughts. Have a good
one and go to my shop, Amanda Land Esports.